(PULSATING)
(LABORED BREATHING)
(GRUNTS)
(PANTING)
I have to say, I was impressed, huh.
You had taken a risk.
Getting your hands dirty.
You know, we were gonna have those biters
for our little Michonne head hunt.
MILTON: (WEAKLY) You were gonna use them
on whoever showed up.
That's right.
Hey, hey.
Because we didn't have them,
you burned them up,
eight of my men died.
(GRUNTS)
And you knew those men, huh?
They kept you safe, kept you fed.
As long as I looked the other way.
Yeah.
Well, it can't be like that anymore.
Time for you to graduate.
Hey.
(GULPS)
I'm gonna tell you a secret.
There's a threat and you end it.
And you don't feel ashamed
about enjoying it.
The smell of gun powder, and you see
the blood, you know what that means?
It means you're alive.
You've won.
You take the heads
so that you don't ever forget.
You kill or you die.
(SNIFFS)
What would your daughter think
about what you are?
She'd be afraid of me.
But if I'd been like this from the start,
she'd be alive today.
Did you kill Andrea?
ANDREA: Milton.
THE GOVERNOR: See, she's still alive.
I'm gonna need her for something.
ANDREA: I heard you in the other room.
You don't have to lose any more
of your men.
Just stop this.
Your friends at the prison,
I'm gonna kill them all.
The people are gonna help me.
I had to stretch the truth a little bit,
but just a little.
Now they're foaming at the mouth.
You, get those tools.
I'm not gonna need them anymore.
Go on.
(TOOLS CLATTERING)
Careful. Pick that up.
Come on. Step to. Let's go.
Hold up.
(SPEAKS SOFTLY) I'll take this.
Put 'em down.
(PANTING)
You're gonna kill her now.
You're gonna show me
that you've learned something.
Milton.
There is no way you are leaving
this room without doing it.
So don't make it hard. Just...
Just do it.
That's it.
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
-(GROANS)
-(GASPS)
-(STABBING)
(CONTINUES STABBING)
(GASPING)
I told you were gonna do it.
And now you're gonna die.
And you're gonna turn.
And you're gonna tear
the flesh from her bones.
(GRUNTS)
In this life now, you kill or you die.
Or you die and you kill.
(THEME MUSIC PLAYING)
(BIRDS CHIRPING)
-Carl.
-(GRUNTS)
I've never seen him this mad.
Even with Lori, he just shut down.
He's still a kid.
It's easy to forget.
You know, Merle never
did nothing like that his whole life.
He gave us a chance.
We're ready.
The deal the Governor offered about me,
you had to think about it.
You had to, I get it.
Yeah.
I'm sorry. I came real close.
But you didn't.
I never thanked you.
For what?
For getting me out there that day,
taking me in.
Well, if you didn't have
that baby formula,
(CLICKS TONGUE) I wouldn't have.
You could have just taken the formula.
Well...
Must have been something else, then.
You know, it was Carl who made the call.
He said you belonged here.
You're one of us.
Remember, they killed
eight men back there.
Five here the last time.
They're no different than the biters.
They're not gonna stop
until they kill us all,
taken everything we've worked so hard for!
We're gonna end this once and for all!
Governor.
This ain't easy to say.
You're gonna have to count us out.
SASHA: This isn't our fight.
TYREESE: We'll fight against the biters,
not other people.
We'll stay here
and defend the children.
When you return, if you want us gone,
no hard feelings.
(SHUDDERED BREATHING)
Thank you.
-(EXHALES)
-(ENGINES STARTING)
Let's roll!
(SNARLING SOFTLY)
(GUNS FIRING)
(GROWLING)
Let's roll!
THE GOVERNOR: Go, go! Move!
MARTINEZ: Come on, come on,
come on, come on.
(TIRES SCREECHING)
(DISTANT CLATTERING)
Give me a flashlight. Let's split up.
You take a group that way.
(WHISPERING) You, bring a group,
follow me.
(DOOR CREAKING)
Go.
-ANDREA: Milton...
-(WEAKLY) When the tools dropped,
I left some pliers on the floor
behind you.
If you can drag... (PANTING)
(GRUNTS) If you can drag
your right foot back,
you can get them.
(GRUNTING)
(ANDREA SIGHS)
That... That's it!
-Oh, God.
-Almost.
I'm gonna get us both out of here.
And you're gonna be okay.
MILTON: No, when you get free,
you are going to find
something very sharp,
and you are going to stab me in the head.
That is what you are going to do.
Keep trying.
ANDREA: (PANTING) Come on.
(DOOR SQUEAKING)
THE GOVERNOR: (WHISPERING) Hey.
Over there.
-(DISTANT CLANGING)
-MAN: What was that?
Shh!
(DISTANT CLATTER)
This way.
(DOOR CLOSES)
(BABY COOING)
We took out a few biters
on the south wall.
Other than that, everything's quiet.
I'll get the next one.
What do you think happens
when they return?
We might have to slip out.
Andrea made it out.
If she's at the prison,
it didn't do her any good.
I'll be right back.
-It's my turn.
-Stay put. I got it.
(DOOR OPENS AND CLOSES)
(GASPS) I got it. I got it.
(PANTING)
Milton?
(MILTON GROANS)
(SIGHS)
Milton.
Why did you stay...
After you found out
your friends were out there?
I wanted to save everyone.
Even the Governor, for a while.
I had a chance to kill him.
What stopped you?
No, this was before.
He was asleep, I had a knife.
But I tried to stop it all another way.
Because I didn't want anyone to die.
(ANDREA SIGHS)
(SPEAKS SOFTLY) I'm still here.
I'm still alive.
Yeah.
You are.
You need to hurry.
-(LOUD EXPLOSION)
-(ALL SHOUTING)
(ALARM WAILING)
Hold your ground!
-(SNARLING)
-(GUN FIRING)
-(GUNS FIRING)
-(SCREAMING)
Hold your ground!
-(ALL CLAMORING)
-(GUNS FIRING)
(ALARM WAILING)
MAN: Get the hell out of here!
(DISTANT GUNFIRE)
I should be there.
Go.
-(COUGHING)
-(GUN FIRING)
MAN: Go! Go, go, go!
Move! Move!
Hit it, hit it, hit it!
-ALLEN: It's not working.
-Go, man!
Shit. It's jammed!
-MAN: Hey!
-We're not going anywhere! Come on!
(BULLETS RICOCHETING)
We did it?
We did it.
Come on down.
(SIGHS)
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa. Don't shoot.
Drop the weapon, son.
Sure.
Here, take it.
-(GUN FIRES)
-(BODY THUDS)
(ALL PANTING)
RICK: We did it. We drove them out.
MICHONNE: We should go after them.
-We should finish it.
-MAGGIE: It is finished.
Didn't you see them
hightail it out of here?
-MICHONNE: They could regroup.
-We can't take the chance.
-He's not gonna stop.
-They're right.
We can't keep living like this.
So we take the fight back to Woodbury?
We barely made it back last time.
I don't care.
Yeah.
-Let's check on the others.
-Come on.
(DOOR SLAMS)
(SIGHS)
(JUDITH COOING)
RICK: Hey.
Hey.
-Dad, I'm coming to Woodbury.
-(SIGHS)
-Carl...
-I did my job out there,
just like all of you.
Took out one of the Governor's soldiers.
HERSHEL: One of his soldiers?
A kid running away?
He stumbled across us.
No, he drew on us.
I'm sorry you had to do that.
It's what I was there for.
I'm going with you.
(DOOR OPENS)
That kid was scared.
He was handing his gun over.
He said he drew.
Carl said it was in defense.
I was there. He didn't have to shoot.
-He had every reason not to.
-Maybe it looked like that to you,
-Hershel.
-Rick.
I'm telling you, he gunned that kid down.
(TIRES SQUEALING)
(HORN BLARING)
Pull over!
Hey! I want this truck over.
Go, go! Pull in front of them!
(TIRES SQUEALING)
What the hell are you doing?
We need to dig in!
-PAUL: It's not worth it.
-That was a slaughter!
You bunch of pussies!
I told you we should've
handled this shit ourselves.
And we're done fighting
for a hole with a half dozen
psychopaths living in it.
They can keep it.
ALLEN: You've seen what they've done.
Attacked us! They killed my boy!
We're going back!
We are not soldiers.
Want us to kill biters? Of course.
-But this is crazy.
-ALLEN: All right, go home!
-You think you're gonna be safe?
-PAUL: I'm going back to Woodbury.
We're not here to settle a grudge.
-(GUN FIRING)
-(ALL SCREAMING)
(FIRING CONTINUES)
(GUN COCKING)
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
(GASPING QUIETLY)
(GUN CLICKS)
(SIGHS)
(EXHALES)
(PLIERS SCRAPING)
Come on.
Okay. Okay.
(ANDREA PANTING)
(SPEAKS SOFTLY) You're still here.
You're still alive. (SIGHS)
(ANDREA GRUNTS)
All right. Okay.
(BREATHES HEAVILY)
RICK: Michonne.
Hershel told me about the boy you shot.
He had a gun.
Hmm.
Was he handing it over?
-He had just attacked us.
-Yeah.
Yes, he had.
Was he handing it over?
I couldn't take the chance.
I didn't kill the walker that killed Dale.
Look what happened.
-Son, that is not the same thing.
-You didn't kill Andrew,
and he came back and killed Mom.
You were in a room with the Governor,
and you let him go.
And then he killed Merle.
I did what I had to do.
Now go.
So he doesn't kill anymore of us.
(METAL CLINKS)
Rick, we're staying.
We don't know where the Governor is.
If he comes back, we'll hold him off.
Just the three of us?
All right.
I appreciate you staying.
MAGGIE: Sure.
(SNARLING)
Quick, quick.
(GRUNTS)
(WALKERS MUNCHING)
(GRUNTS AND SNARLS)
(WALKERS SNARLING)
(GRUNTS)
-(THUDS)
-(DARYL GASPS)
(GASPING)
(SNARLING)
(GASPING) Come on.
Come on.
-(MILTON SNARLS)
-(ANDREA GASPING)
-(CHAINS RATTLES)
-(GRUNTS)
-(GASPING)
-(MILTON SNARLING)
(SCREAMING)
-(CHAINS RATTLING)
-(ANDREA SCREAMING)
-(ANDREA SCREAMS)
-(MILTON GROWLS)
(THUDS)
(OBJECTS RUMBLING)
KAREN: Tyreese!
-It's me! Don't...
-Get down!
TYREESE: Karen!
Karen, are you okay?
-I'm fine!
-TYREESE: Where's the Governor?
KAREN: He fired on everyone.
He killed them all.
-TYREESE: Why are you with them?
-They saved me.
We're coming out!
(RICK SIGHS)
We're coming out.
(RICK EXHALES)
TYREESE: What are you doing here?
We were coming
to finish this
until we saw
what the Governor did.
TYREESE: He... He killed them?
(SOFTLY) Yeah.
Karen told us
Andrea hopped the wall
going for the prison.
She never made it.
She might be here.
RICK: This is where he had
Glenn and Maggie.
TYREESE: The Governor held people here?
DARYL: He did more than hold them.
Will you open it?
(SOFTLY) One, two...
(SOFTLY) Andrea!
I tried to stop them.
You're burning up.
(ANDREA GROANS)
Judith, Carl,
the rest of them...
Us.
The rest of us.
Are they alive?
Yeah, they're alive.
(ANDREA SIGHS)
It's good you found them.
No one can
make it alone now.
I never could.
I just didn't want
anyone to die.
(ANDREA EXHALES)
-I can do it myself.
-No.
No, I have to.
While I still can.
Please?
I know how the safety works.
Well, I'm not going anywhere.
I tried.
(SOFTLY) Yeah.
You did.
(DOOR CLOSES)
(GUNSHOT)
(METAL CLINKS)
(INDISTINCT TALKING)
What is this?
They're gonna join us.
(THEME MUSIC PLAYING)